EXPEDITORS

OCEAN EXPORTS

ENGLISH TOUGH?

Harmin Vira

Mobile: 519-933-8208

Email: harminvira@gmail.com

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

Post-Graduation Diploma in Logistics and Supply Chain Management. Four years of experience in providing top-notch Operations and Customer Service in the field of Supply Chain Management and Logistics.

Experienced team player, great communication skills, and enjoy being collaborative. Achieved Best Performer Award in Maersk Logistics (Damco).

EDUCATION

Logistics and Supply Chain Management Ontario College Graduate Certificate

Sept 2017 - Apr 2018

Fanshawe College, London ON

Studied Operations Management, Transportation, and Logistics, Inventory and Distribution Management, International Law and subjects related to Supply Chain Management.

Bachelor of Financial Markets

Oct 2009 - Apr 2012

Mumbai University, India

Studied Corporate Governance, CRM, Global Capital Markets, Portfolio Management and major subjects related to Commerce and Trade.

TECHNICAL AND OTHER SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook and Access.
- Strategic thinking and ability to work effectively in fast-paced environment.
- Possess Analytical and Problem-solving skills.
- Adaptability to work efficiently in changing environment.
- Great communicator; fluent in English, Hindi, and Gujarati.
- Excellent organizational and project management skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Logistics Coordinator Golden Freight Forwarding, Canada

May 2018-Present

Job Profile:

- Client Coordination for Export shipments.
- Customs filing and shipping documentation.
- Booking and trucking coordination.
- Customer service and inside sales support.

Harmin Vira

Mobile: 519-933-8208

Email: harminvira@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, continued

Move Manager for Relocations JVK Pacific Ltd (JVK International), India

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017

Job Profile:

- Coordinated all Air and Sea shipments as required, liaising with agents, shippers, JVK International offices.
- Price negotiation with carriers, rate filing and quoting the customers.
- Inventory management and shipment planning through ERP system.
- Responsible for creating work orders and coordinated with third party vendors.
- Ensured all shipments were handled efficiently and professionally with Relocation Coordinators for Pacific and Africa locations.
- Managed JVK Papua New Guinea(PNG) operations with FIDI Quality standards.
- Supervised and handled shipments for remote locations in Pacific region.

Senior Operations Executive for Project Freight Forwarding BDP International-Mumbai, India

Aug 2014 - May 2015

Job Profile:

- Managed Project and General cargo coordination for Export and Import shipments.
- Freight negotiation and container booking for Over Dimensional Cargo and General cargo.
- Pricing and transportation coordination through scheduling with drivers based on client and geographical needs for cost efficiency.
- Responsible for container stuffing instructions and adherence to shipping requirements.
- Shipping instructions to carriers, ISF and AMS filing for US shipments, shipment pre-alert, document dispatch and BL release.

Logistics Coordinator-Supply Chain Management Damco-Mumbai, India

Feb 2013 - Aug 2014

Job Profile:

- Managed logistics co-ordination for Air and Sea shipments.
- Vendor management and coordinated with shippers for bookings and volume forecast.
- Implemented new clients as per Standard Operating Procedure.
- Coordinated with Container Freight Station (CFS) team for cargo stuffing plans.
- Responsible for carrier requirements and Port gate timelines.
- Shipping Instructions to the carrier and updating clients on shipment status.
- Shipping documentation, ISF/AMS filing.